Case 2: A Software Reuse Measure Developed at  MBA Technologie

prolem relevent
Most software development companies do not assess their success at reuse.

The company obtained high reuse in its software development by leveraging of existing components that were mapped to an enterprise-level model. 
The development and subsequent dissemination of a reuse measure that can be applied to enterprise-level model-based reuse efforts would enable the researchers to conduct an in-depth analysis of MBA Technologies’ reuse success across multiple completed projects. Further, a measure would provide the means for continued monitoring of reuse success in software projects


Built
+ Approach
A high-level measure in the ﬁeld setting, decisions had to be made about how to assess and count modiﬁed component reuse, partial component reuse, generated code, and multiple layers of abstraction.
+ Method
A reuse rate measure that allowed the researchers to assess the reuse rate, or reuse percentage, of the participating organization for subsequent case study researc

+ Design, Development and Demo
- The concept of the reuse rate was obtained from software reuse literature, which served as the theoretical foundation for the development of the reuse metric
- Assessing and reporting the reuse rate for a project in the participating organization demonstrated the measure’s feasibility and efﬁcacy



eveluate

The measure was used to assess the reuse rates of ﬁve projects at MBA Technologies, with sizes varying from 57 KLOC to 143 KLOC. The assessed total project reuse rate for nongenerated code ranged from 50.5 percent to 76.0 percent

